Address: 23 Parry Court, Nottingham NG3 2NG

Mobile: +447961299118

Email: adinfosam@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/adinfosam

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/samuelodusami

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Git/GitHub

Corel Draw

Adobe Photoshop

WordPress, CRM

SEO/SEM

Web application development

Mobile applications

APIs

Web analytics

Web UI/UX design

Graphics Arts

Brand & Logo

Copywriting

Content development

Design

Google analytics

Office 365

PowerPoint

Excel

Samuel Odusami

Digital Marketer, UI/UX, Webmaster

PERSONAL SUMMARY

In the last 12 years, I have worked in web development, digital marketing and content strategy. One major strength that I possess is my drive, passion and commitment to get things done by working with colleagues, superiors, clients and other stakeholders.

I am interested in developing and managing platforms that can enable companies provide superior products and services for their customers, measure their impact on the business as well as operating as a sustainable and inclusive organization.

I am looking at working with companies and businesses that put technology at the heart of their operations and I am keen to collaborate in managing web, applications, campaigns and processes that can be a force for profitable and positive change

CAREER HISTORY

NYSUT STUDIOS – Lagos, Nigeria SENIOR DIGITAL STRATEGIST & DEVELOPER Jul 2009 - Present

Oversee the group's web and digital marketing projects by developing overarching design, content strategy, analytics, and performance reporting for roaster clients and critical projects.

- Conceptualise design and content strategy
- Supervise and oversee content development and management.
- Provide design prototypes and wireframes for web and applications
- Develop user interface and user experience guidelines for critical projects
- Collaborate with the frontend and backend team to code in HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Providing web analytics and performance management for key accounts and website projects.
- Oversee web and mobile applications customer supports and issue resolution
- Oversee weekly and periodic project reviews with roster and project-based clients.
- Ensure web and application projects are delivered according to brief, industry standard and quality.
- Managing all digital marketing campaigns across social, search, display, video and native advertising platforms.

SBI MEDIA UK – London

HEAD DIGITAL & ATL STRATEGY July 2015 – Till Date

Manage end-to-end media strategy and business development across digital, public relations and content development. I also oversee

- Develop unique strategies and builds upon current client strategies within the digital arena to meet/exceed objectives.
- Executes projects to be high quality, on time and cost-effective/on budget.
- Fosters timeline development and monitors progress, ensuring deadlines are met.
- Manages overall project scope and ensures staffing assumptions adhere to budget
- Develops strong, trusting relationships between clients and agency partners, providing leadership and support during strategy, ideation, and execution.
- Manages client expectations, bringing issues/concerns to clients' attention before they become problems, offering

PERSONAL SKILLS

Problem solver Creative

Team player

Critical Thinker

Initiative

Attention to detail

Punctual

Experienced

Team player

Project manager

Analytical

PROFESSIONAL

Experienced marketer

Fluent - English

Media Integra – Lagos, Nigeria

HEAD, WEB & DIGITAL STRATEGY Feb 2015 – July 2015

Nikon Nigeria – Lagos, Nigeria

ECOMMERCE & DIGITAL EXEC. Apr 2014 – Feb 2015

Mainsail Media - Lagos, Nigeria

WEB & DIGITAL ANALYST Jul 2009 – March 2013

M2 Magazine – Lagos, Nigeria

TRAINEE CONTENT Jun 2006 - Aug 2006

KEY COMPETENCIES AND SKILLS

Web Development

- Advanced knowledge of HTML5, CSS, XML, Bootstrap5 and JavaScript.
- Proficient with Git, GitHub, CMS platforms and WordPress
- Advanced knowledge of Google analytics and search, social and display analytics including A/B testing
- Advanced use of Corel Draw, Photoshop and Canva
- Creative, business writing and copywriting for websites and projects.
- Digital and brand design for online and offline use.
- Business development and client relationship experience and management
- Abreast with global standards and procedures in web, data and intellectual property security and management.

Professional

- Self-starter and team player with project management experience.
- Quick grasp of brief objectives, project requirement and complexities.
- Able to work with tight schedules and deliver before deadlines.
- Passionate about knowledge sharing and human capacity development.
- Strong understanding of data security, privacy and global standards in digital and web technologies.

Personal

- Passionate about people and collaboration.
- Excellent interpersonal communication skills and networking.
- Outgoing and passionate about meeting new people.
- Dependable and trustworthy to deliver as promised.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Professional Certificate in Azure, AWS, Python In-view

Professional Certificate in HTML, CSS & 2022

Javascript

Nottingham Trent University, 2021 - 2022

M.A International Relations

University of Lagos 2012 - 2014

M.A. Diplomatic & Strategic Studies

Olabisi Onabanjo University 2004 - 2008

B.A. Mass communication (Advertising)

REFERENCES – Available on request.